[
    {
        "question": "1",
        "answer": "I’ll give you another example of how friendliness is related to survival."
    },
    {
        "question": "2",
        "answer": "Dr. Hare and his colleagues designed an experiment with chimpanzees and bonobos."
    },
    {
        "question": "3",
        "answer": "Although the two are genetically similar, they are different in nature."
    },
    {
        "question": "4",
        "answer": "To study their cooperative behavior, Dr. Hare’s team set up a device which required two individuals to pull both ends of a rope at the same time in order to access food on a board."
    },
    {
        "question": "5",
        "answer": "When placed with partners that the chimpanzees knew, they were able to work together to get the food"
    },
    {
        "question": "6",
        "answer": "However, when paired with new partners, the chimpanzees usually failed to get the food, and when they occasionally succeeded, they did not share the food with their partner."
    },
    {
        "question": "7",
        "answer": "The bonobos, on the other hand, got along much better than the chimpanzees"
    },
    {
        "question": "8",
        "answer": "They solved the problem regardless of which individual they were paired with, and they were also more willing to share the food."
    },
    {
        "question": "9",
        "answer": "This research shows that bonobos have a cooperative and friendly nature."
    },
    {
        "question": "10",
        "answer": "experts suggest that their nature has helped their species survive."
    },
    {
        "question": "11",
        "answer": "Without these characteristics, they could have faced extinction."
    }
]